<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hu-speaks.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://hu-speaks.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-03T22:50:06+00:00</updated><id>https://hu-speaks.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hu</title><subtitle>This is where Hu speaks on topics related to China. In this era when international tensions are high, The people, the normal people who does not work in governments or media, need to understand each other. But to understand China is to misunderstand China. Let&apos;s talk about my particular version of such a misunderstanding. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">China is self-consistent</title><link href="https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/alt-model/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China is self-consistent"/><published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/alt-model</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/alt-model/"><![CDATA[<p>China has put two images to the world. First, there is Mao’s China, when the Bolsheviks and the former poor peasants “ruled the country”. Of course, Mao is the one who was actually in power, but this fact did not actually contradict with “poor people’s ruling”, since Mao’s cult of personality envelops the lower-class of China, completely. There were intricate dynamics between Mao and his followers, but that’s a topic for another time. Mao’s China, ideologically, adhered with the Soviet Union’s original vision of communism, a society with no presence of oppressors, and thus the vast majority of people can live better lives. Nonetheless, for some reason, people suffered, arguably more than any other non-communist country.</p> <p>Deng Xiaoping, the successor of Mao who was not handpicked by him, subverts this poor, communist image of China by embracing capitalism to an extent. Fast forward 40 years, China has become the major manufacturer for the whole world. In the golden age of 2010s, you can see product made in China from almost all stores. China has become an authoritarian regime with a booming economy, with no lack of CEOs, bankers, and real estate company owners. These people, once vilified in Mao’s China, are calling the shots. The government officials are still in control, but in a more shadowy way, hiding behind the veil of pseudo-companies.</p> <p>The current ruler of China, Xi, has told the Chinese people this order: don’t use the old 30 years to negate the new 30 years, and don’t use the new 30 years to negate the old 30 years either. What he is saying is about reconciling these two images of China, Mao’s communism and Deng’s capitalism. Xi, with his unquestionable authority, wants to stop people from seeing these two eras as contradictions, but as a sort of natural progression, both necessary to achieve the final utopia, true communism, where people do not get things based on how much they have worked, but rather on how much they need.</p> <p>How is this possible? How can the poor peasants, who had the right to execute the merchant class and discriminate their kindreds (called the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Black_Categories">five black categories </a> “), understand that in current China, business owners are de facto a part of the ruling class? How can the entrepreneurs, with money and a (albeit small) share of power, come to terms with the fact that, in theory, they should be eliminated? There is no easy way to see China as a continuation. Netizens in China interested in politics have split into two communities: the leftists who adore Mao’s vision of China, and the rightists who hold libertarian views. At this very moment, they are engaging in an eternal debate, often escalating to personal attacks, about the future of China. Sadly, all these debates are for nothing, because these online Chinese folks don’t have a say in the future of China at all. No matter what they think and what they say, they have no choice but to follow the orders given by the people who are actually in charge.</p> <p>In the end, you might think, that China does not have anything new at all. Mao’s vision is essentially the Soviet Union’s vision, and Deng’s vision is the same as any other authoritarian regime. However, we current have Xi’s China, and Xi’s China is different from Mao’s China or Deng’s China. It is, roughly speaking, an amalgamation of the former two. It essentially argues that, if communism wants to succeed in the world where it is surrounded by capitalistic regimes, it has to beat capitalists at their own game. In other words, it has to out-compete them. It needs to demonstrate that a communist regime is more efficient at producing goods than any other capitalist regime. A communist’s vision is only viable after this feat has been achieved. Therefore, Mao’s old China was useful in the sense that it beat Chinese folks into believing communism in a religious kind of way. But it had this huge blindspot, the economy. Deng realized this deficit, and corrects it by introducing a version of “controlled capitalism”, capitalism under the control of a vastly powerful government. Now, as China would argue to the world, it can produce products that are cheaper, more in number, and higher in quality than any other country. And it achieves this by deliberately avoiding converting to a liberal democracy. China’s model is a way of organizing society that extract the competitiveness of a free market without making anything “free”; everything is always under control of the CCP.</p> <p>This is a trend amongst experts on China in the US and Europe that characterizes China as a capitalist authoritarian regime under the veil of communism. I argue that it is exactly the reverse: China is a communist regime under the guise of capitalism. It is always trying to make communism come true. Capitalism is but a tool in China’s toolbox.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="China"/><category term="politics"/><category term="philosophy"/><category term="communism"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[how to reconcile Mao and Deng's different visions]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Democracy has a stability problem</title><link href="https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/democracy-is-unstable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Democracy has a stability problem"/><published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/democracy-is-unstable</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hu-speaks.github.io/blog/2024/democracy-is-unstable/"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t think many US citizens would disagree, when I say that the US suffered a humiliating defeat in Afghanistan on August 30th, 2021. It seems that, when the US tries to implement democracies in other less well-developed countries, there is hardly any success. Sure, several counterexamples come to mind, like post-war Japan, south Korea, and Taiwan. But we also have Vietnam, Cuba, and Afghanistan, and the failure over these countries cannot be attributed to a lack of effort by the US government. So what went wrong over there? Is there any reason why some countries can adopt a functional democracy and prosper, while for others this seems almost impossible? Yes, different countries have different cultures and histories, and sometimes the mind of the incidental leader of a country can make or break a democracy. However, if we zoom out to look at the big picture, democracy as a way of ruling a country seems to have an inherent problem: compared with dictatorship, it is simple unstable.</p> <p>It may be more enlightening if I talk about stability in the most general term possible. For any system, either made of inanimate objects or made of human beings, stability means a tendency for this system to bounce back to its original state when subject to some kind of disturbance. This is also called negative feedback. Biologists would say that a living human body is stable (or at least metastable), since it has many negative feedback mechanisms to push the human body system back to normal if it deviates from it. The premise, which is true in most cases, is that the world is riddled with noises and disturbances. The natural conclusion, then, is that, for any system to exist long term, it has to be stable (or at least metastable). Talking in technical terms of stability isn’t too helpful when considering the problem of democracy, since it is near impossible to build a mathematical model for it. But what we can do is to revert the logic a bit: if something exists in nature for a long time, then more likely than not, it has to be stable.</p> <p>So what’s the problem? Democracies in the US have existed for at least 200 years, which is long enough time for anyone to regard it as strong evidence for the stability of democracy. I agree that, in the absence of an existential war (by that I mean blood-spilling, nasty wars happening on the homeland, not foreign wars from a distance or cold wars), democracy seems to be stable. But no country is founded without an existential war. the Peoples’ republic of China is founded on a civil war, the US is founded on the revolutionary war, and South Korea is founded on the Korea war, etc. In order to win this founding war, the winning side has to have a strong leader who can exert total control the military as well as citizens. An actual democracy is too slow and scattered to be able to win this war. Even ancient Rome knows this idea.</p> <p>Now, after this founding war is won, the winning side is naturally a dictatorship, which has a pyramid structure where one man directly controls a bunch of other men, and each of those men directly controls a bunch of lower-rank men, and so on. The top man, George Washington in the case of US, and Mao in the case of China, enjoys limitless power. It is nothing short of a miracle for this man to willingly relinquish this power. To do so is to directly oppose one’s human nature, and arguable no moral teachings can provide a surefire way to guarantee this to happen. This is not the end of the story though, because the power vacuum caused by the top man stepping down invites new conflicts. This conflict would be in the frameworks of democracy, in other words, an election. Nonetheless, it is still a power struggle, and the side with better control of the subsidiaries would tend to win this struggle. So how can you guarantee that this new leader who is elected democratically, does not aim to enjoy this power forever? Maybe this leader will not do this because of their own conscience, or can’t do this because of rules and guardrails of democracy, but what about the next successor? The next next successor?</p> <p>Eventually, the rules and guardrails will age, and people’s adherence to democratic values fluctuate. This is, in my opinion, the fundamental issue raised by Trump. He exposes the fact that democracies will always run into the stability issue, and the result will always be uncertain.</p> <p>Another clear example of the issue of stability is the Nazi Germany. Before Nazis rose to power, Germany is a democracy. But (arguably) the German people decides that they are bigger issue to face than preserving democracy; they need to restore Germany to its former glory more than they need democracy. So, as the result, democracy is gone.</p> <p>Unfortunately, we, the human race, have not cracked the code of democracy. This is simply no surefire way to establish one from scratch. This is even no surefire way to preserve a democracy. A democratic regime is always sliding, ever so slightly, from its perfect equilibrium, and no matter how much effort we put into pushing it back to normal, there is always the possibility that it all crumbles down. Maybe next year. Maybe tomorrow.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="the"/><category term="West"/><category term="politics"/><category term="philosophy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[why can't everyone enjoy a functional democracy]]></summary></entry></feed>